Ollie Husband • Senior/Lead Front End Developer

+447988239814 · olliehusband.com · olliehusband@me.com · github.com/Ollie-H

Profile

I am a focused and ambitious Senior/Lead Front End Developer with solid experience creating sites, applications and tooling for a wide range of clients and sectors including financial, commercial, retail, automotive and advertising for global recognised companies such as BBC and Saatchi & Saatchi. I have a broad knowledge of JavaScript, am proficient in a number of modern frameworks (React, Angular, Vue, Redux) and have experience managing and mentoring front end teams.

My passion for web development coupled with my ability to pick up new skills quickly means that I stay on top of most relevant technologies and directions. I achieve this by attending various conferences and talks around Europe and spending my free time experimenting and getting to grips with modern development trends that may not be a fit for my current projects. I'm currently most excited about functional programming patterns with tools such as Ramda and ReasonMI and modern API approaches such as GraphyQI.

Due to my previous exposure and familiarity with backend technologies I am also comfortable taking ownership of the full stack and have experience in Node, PHP, Python and Scala as well as various database languages. I also have experience in Agile, prototyping and waterfall development methodologies as well as tools like JIRA.

In recent positions I have been given the responsibility to perform in a lead capacity, where I can help and mentor more junior developers. I have found this to be a rewarding part of my role, It has also helped to learn the technologies better through teaching.

I also have an interest and good understanding of UX and design, and I will always try to work with designers to help them translate their ideas into usable and scalable systems.

Experience

Undisclosed (name omitted) · May 2016 – August 2018 · Front End Manager (Senior)

Undisclosed are a financial tech startup that specialise in using big data and predictive analytics to outperform the market. I was brought in at an early stage to lead the Front End team and build their web based Saas platform. As the company pivoted in to other areas I was tasked with building other systems such as portfolio management applications, data visualisation tools to display analytical data and internal tooling for operations and data corrections.

- Built various client applications and tooling using React / JSX / Redux / SASS / Webpack / Flow / Angular 2 / Typescript / D3 / Ramda
- Built API services using Node / Scala / Python
- Managed Front End and API teams of up to 5, including off site developers
- Developed an understanding of financial markets, company fundamentals and stock market terminology and accounting
- Implemented TDD testing using Jest / Scala test / pytest

Williams Lea / TAG · Mar 2016 – May 2016 · Senior Front End Developer (Contractor)

- Responsible for maintaining and adding features to an existing large client SaaS platform
- Used Backbone / Marionette / Bootstrap
- Testing using Jasmine

BBC · Aug 2015 – Mar 2016 · Senior Software Developer (Contractor)

I joined BBC at the start of a project planning to modernise their Academy platform which specialises training and development designed to support and educate the BBC and the wider industry. My main deliverable here was to work with the designers and backend engineers to build the new Front End in React / Flux.

- Lead front end build and delivery of new BBC academy platform, using React (Universal), Redux, Sass, Node
- Rebuilt large parts of current BBC pattern libraries into React components
- Built and maintained container image for continuous integration of the front end build
- Worked with AWS cloud search for fast indexing of searching of large amounts of course data
- Worked closely with designers to maintain strict BBC accessibility and branding guidelines
- Implemented BDD testing using cucumber

Saatchi & Saatchi · Oct 2014 – Aug 2015 · Senior Front End Developer

Saatchi are a world leading advertising agency with an array of global clients. I joined them to help create digital campaigns, maintain current brand sites and build internal tooling.

- Built sites and applications using modern Front End technologies (Backbone, BEM, Gulp/Grunt, Browserify/Require) and Jasmine for unit testing.
- Helped to restructure the stack used on new projects by building the JS boilerplate.
- Built internal systems such as a digital display banner upload and management app and recruitment tool.
- Explored new technologies, such as React/Flux and gave small talks on pro's and con's, as well as attending conferences and talks throughout Europe on behalf of the agency.

Saddington Baynes · Mar 2013 – Oct 2014 · Full Stack Developer

- Solely responsible for full stack development on client and internal projects. Including an in store and online configurator for Infiniti.
- Built back end systems for Infiniti in PHP/Slim/MySQL
- Established version control in their process with Github and introduced continuous integration by building a basic deployment server in PHP with the Bitbucket API.
- Experimented with cross channel development prototypes such as Leap Motion

Morrisons · Sept 2013 – Mar 2014 · Front End Developer (Contractor)

Candi · Nov 2011 – Sept 2012 · Junior Front End Developer **Connect** · Jul 2011 – Nov 2011 · Junior Front End Developer

Education

2007 - 2011

Multimedia computing · Second class BSC degree (sandwich award) · De Montfort University

2005 - 2007

A-level · Business studies, ICT, Art and Design, General Studies · Trinity High School Sixth Form

Key Skills

- Javascript programming ES5/ES6
- Typescript / Flow
- JS frameworks React / Redux / Angular >= 2 / Vue / Backbone
- Web content accessibility standards
- Standards and cross browser compliant HTML5, CSS
- React Native
- CSS preprocessors Sass/ Less / PostCSS
- Flexbox
- Data visualisation D3/ Plotly / VX
- JS unit testing and BDD Jasmine / Jest
- Continuous Integration Jenkins
- Docker building and maintaining images
- Agile methodologies and using JIRA
- Extensive version control experience GIT, Mercurial and SVN
- Real time application development Websockets / pusher
- Node Express, Mongo
- Scala Play / Scalatest / Scalacache
- Python Django and Django Rest experience
- PHP/MySQL

References are available on request.